yapsody.com 2014-03-26

# Yapsody Privacy Policy | PCI Certified

Welcome to YAPSODY, the professional ticketing system turns event organizers in professional presenters without the restrictive lock-in periods or high fees imposed by other professional ticketing systems. 

Please review the following Privacy Policy that sets forth how YAPSODY collects and uses User Data and other information. By using YAPSODY, you agree to the policies set forth below and in YAPSODY’s Terms of Use.

Please refer to YAPSODY's _Terms of Use_ for definitions of capitalized terms appearing in this Privacy Policy.

#### USER DATA COLLECTION, USAGE & SHARING

User Data Collection by YAPSODY

YAPSODY may collect User Data from Users while interacting with or using YAPSODY in any manner including, without limitation, while registering with YAPSODY; engaging in contact with YAPSODY or a Seller (e.g., via email); purchasing Merchandise on YAPSODY whether from YAPSODY or a Seller; and paying for services provided by YAPSODY or a Seller via Electronic Payment or otherwise.

YAPSODY may collect Electronic Payment Data as necessary to facilitate Electronic Payment Transactions whether involving a Seller’s Online Store or otherwise. Electronic Payment Data will not be shared with other Users (including Sellers) or third-parties except for applicable Payment Gateways for the sole purposes of processing Electronic Payment Transactions. In such cases, the Electronic Payment Data shall be collected by YAPSODY upon “check-out” at time of payment and shall be securely transmitted via the respective Payment Gateway’s API and in accordance with said Payment Gateway’s prescribed procedures. Any Electronic Payment Data collected in connection with a Transaction involving Seller Merchandise will be done so by YAPSODY and transmitted to the Seller’s selected Payment Gateway on behalf of the Seller as the merchant of record. YAPSODY shall in no case directly provide seller with access to Electronic Payment Data. 

YAPSODY does not store Electronic Payment Data provided in connection with a Transaction except for the last approximately 4 characters of any financial account provided by a User for making Electronic Payments. Such information may be provided to an applicable Seller for identification and sales reconciliation purposes only. YAPSODY may collect Non-Personal User Data. Such Data may be collected passively through digital means, by requesting it from the User, or from third parties who collect the data independently. Non-Personal User Data cannot and shall not be used to identify Users. 

User Data Collection by Sellers

Sellers are authorized to collect Personal User Data and Non-Personal User Data at their discretion in connection with a Seller’s Online Store. Any such Data provided in connection therewith may be available to the respective Seller and to that extent outside the control of YAPSODY. YAPSODY may also make such Data available to a particular Seller with respect to Users who have engaged in Transactions involving that Seller’s Merchandise. Alternatively, Sellers are not authorized to collect Electronic Payment Data in connection with a Seller’s Online Store. Users should refrain from providing any Electronic Payment Data via a Seller’s Online Store or in any correspondence with a Seller except at the point of “check-out” at time of payment. Users are instructed to inform YAPSODY in the event that an attempt to collect Electronic Payment Data has occurred other than upon “check-out” at time of payment. YAPSODY shall not be responsible for any injuries or damages that may occur as a result of a User providing Electronic Payment Data other than as prescribed hereunder.

Links to Third-Party Websites

This Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites that are not owned or operated by YAPSODY or its parent company, despite the fact that links to such third-party websites may appear on YAPSODY. Users should contact those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

User Data Retention

YAPSODY may retain a User’s Personal User Data as long as that User continues to use YAPSODY. Even after a User stops using YAPSODY and/or closes his/her YAPSODY account, YAPSODY may nevertheless retain Personal User Data as permitted or required under applicable law. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a User’s Personal User Data may be archived on YAPSODY system backups for an indefinite period of time. 

#### COOKIES

When accessing YAPSODY, Users may have "cookies" placed on their browsers to help YAPSODY analyze usage in order to improve its products and services and to provide tailored content (including advertising) and functionality (such as ability to use the Box Office without having to continuously reenter a password). Some cookies may be programed to last for a single session while others may be programmed to last for a particular period of time. While YAPSODY recommends that Users leave cookies turned on, Users nevertheless have the option to manage how “cookies” are handled through browser's option settings. 

#### OPTING OUT

Users can "opt out" of receiving YAPSODY marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in marketing emails received from YAPSODY. However, Users cannot opt out of non-marketing, informational emails about a User’s account or a User’s transactions or emails containing updates about YAPSODY unless User contacts YAPOSDY support with a request to that effect AND terminates his/her YAPSODY account. Even after User opts out of all communications, YAPSODY will continue to store User’s Personal User Data and Non-Personal User Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

In the case of emails sent by Sellers to Users with whom a Seller has transacted Merchandise, such emails are not sent through YAPSODY. Consequently, Users wishing to opt out of such emails must do so directly with the Seller or the email system that the Seller is using to send such emails.

#### SECURITY

YAPSODY takes reasonable steps to protect Personal User Data from unauthorized access and misuse. However, Internet and email transmission are not completely secure. YAPSODY recommends that USERS not send sensitive information to YAPSODY via email or disclose such information via the Internet.

User Data is stored on servers located in the United States. Users accessing YAPSODY from outside the United States should be aware that all User Data is handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy and United States privacy laws, which may be different than the privacy laws in other countries. 

#### CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

Use of User Data

Generally speaking, except as otherwise set forth hereunder, YAPSODY uses Personal User Data and Electronic Payment Data for the purpose for which it was provided. For example, if a User contacts YAPSODY, YAPSODY will use any User Data provided in said correspondence to effectively respond to the User. Similarly, if a User provides Electronic Payment Data in connection with a Transaction, YAPSODY will user such Data to facilitate payment for the Transaction.

YAPSODY may use any Personal User Data internally as follows: for improving the Software, the Content, and YAPSODY’s offerings; for protecting YAPSODY and its Users against fraud; for managing Users’ accounts; to contact Users or display Content for marketing and advertising purposes, including to inform Users of events that may be of interest to them; to contact Users to inform them about issues related to their YAPSODY accounts and transactions.

Because Non-Personal User Data cannot be used to personally identify Users, YAPSODY may use such Data for any lawful purpose, which includes sharing such data with third parties. 

If YAPSODY intends to use any User Data in any other manner, the applicable Users will be provided advanced notice thereof or the applicable Users’ consent will be obtained.
